twi-global.com 2017-11-21

# Privacy Statement

### Information about our organisation and website

Information and communication technologies play a fundamental role in the activities of an organisation like TWI Ltd. We are based in the UK. 

Our principal activities are:

  * Engineering consultancy
  * Engineering research
  * Engineering training
  * Professional engineering society
  * Events   

Our privacy policy covers TWI Ltd’s websites:

 Organisation name: |  TWI Ltd  
---|---  
 Address: |  Granta Park, Great Abington  
 City: |  Cambridge, CB21 6AL  
 Country: |  UK  
 Controller: |  The Data Controller  
 ICO Registration: |  Z5611956  
 Websites: | 

www.twi-global.com       

This privacy and cookie use policy explains how we use any personal information we collect about you when you use these websites. 

**Anonymous Access  
**You can access our websites' home pages and browse much of our site without disclosing your personal information. 

**Other websites  
**Our websites include links to external websites and a link to:

  * Barclays Bank secure payment system

  * RBS WorldPay secure payment system   

Such third party web service providers may collect personal information about our visitors. This privacy and cookie use policy only applies to these websites so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy and cookie use policies.   

## Cookies

A [cookie ](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie) is a small amount of data which is sent to your browser from a website's computer and is stored on your device's hard drive.  These pieces of information are used to improve services for you.

**What we do use cookies for**

  * ensuring the websites work as you’d expect

  * enabling a service to recognise your device with your permission so you don’t have to give the same information several times during one task

  * recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don’t need to do it for every web page requested anonymously measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there’s enough capacity to ensure they are fast

  * allowing you to share pages with social networking sites such as Facebook and Twitter

  * personalising our site to you to help you get what you need faster.

**What we do not use cookies for**

  * collecting personally identifiable information unless you have given your express permission and consent

  * collecting personally sensitive information unless you have given your express permission and consent

  * pass data onto third party advertising networks

  * pass personally identifiable data onto third parties

  * paying sales commissions or trading in your personal and web session data.

**Cookie notice for users**

**By continuing to use our websites, you are agreeing with us that we can place the types of cookies as described on your device.**

**If you do not agree with the use of cookies as described in this section, please follow the steps for controlling and deleting cookies  provided in 'How to control and delete cookies' below and navigate away from our website.**

**Cookies set by us for improving our service to you **

The following cookies are used by Google Analytics, and are applied to every page of the TWI site. Google Analytics set cookies to help TWI accurately estimate the number of visitors to the website and volumes of usage. This is to ensure that the service is available when you want it and fast.

**Name:_utmz**

Purpose: logs where a visitor came from, e.g. a search engine or from another website

Typical content: no personal information about you, only a randomly generated identification number linked to information about your computer and your browser

Domain: .twi-global.com; nsirc.co.uk

Expires: 6 months after it was last set on your device 

**Name:_utma**

Purpose: logs each user’s number of visits, the time of the first visit, the previous visit and the current visit

Typical content: no personal information about you, only a randomly generated identification number linked to information about your computer and your browser

Domain: .twi-global.com; nsirc.co.uk

Expires: 2 years after your last visit to the website

**Name:_utmb**

Purpose: logs when a user starts their visit

Typical content: no personal information about you, only a randomly generated identification number linked to information about your computer and your browser

Domain: .twi-global.com; nsirc.co.uk

Expires: 30 minutes after your visit or after 30 minutes of inactivity

**Name:_utmc**

Purpose: logs when a user ends their visit

Typical content: no personal information about you, only a randomly generated identification number linked to information about your computer and your browser

Domain: .twi-global.com; nsirc.co.uk

Expires: when you close your browser

For further details on the cookies set by Google Analytics, please refer to the [Google Code ](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies "Google Code Cookies")website.

**Name: ASP.NET_SessionID**

Purpose: session identifier cookies are set if you have login credentials after registering with our website and agreeing our terms and conditions. The cookie recognises your movement around the site as being from one computer.

Typical content: information about the session but the cookie itself does not contain any personal information

Domain:.twi-global.com; nsirc.co.uk

Expires: when you close your browser

**Name: RememberMe (2 cookies) **

Purpose: after entering your username and password in the login page, you can check this box allowing the website to remember your login details on your next visit so that you do not have to repeat the login process. These are ‘persistent cookies’ which are only set by your actions.

Typical content: username and password and a session verification cookies to authenticate your login details against our login database.

Domain:.twi-global.com/login/?ReturnUrl=/home/ ; nsirc.co.uk/login/?ReturnUrl=/home/

Expires: never until the logged in user clicks the ‘log out’ option

**Cookies set by third-party services**

Throughout the site we use the services of external service providers to enhance the visitors’ experience. They set cookies to enhance their service or to track usage or to validate users. These cookies are only set when the page that uses that service is visited for example  when you select a link and opt in to such a service. TWI is not responsible for the content of third party websites and does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for further information.

**Google Analytic cookies for improving  our service**

Google Analytics is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google stores the information collected by the cookie on servers in the United States. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google does not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. To give you additional control over Google Analytics cookies, Google provides an opt-out plug-in for most common website browsers. 

For further details on the cookies set by Google Analytics, please refer to the [Google Code ](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies "Google Code Cookies")website.

**Cookies set by ‘Share This’ **

The ShareThis widget places the following cookies on your computer to make their service easier to use and to measure the size of our website’s audience. ** **

**Name: _uset**

Purpose: identifies when a user had had a cookie set on their computer so that the task is not repeated in the next eight hours

Typical content: contains the text ‘true’ or ‘false’ depending on whether you have enabled cookie sharing

Domain: .sharethis.com

Expires: 8 hours after being set on your device

**Name: _stid**

Purpose: identifies users with topics of interest, based upon the content they consume and share

Typical content: a randomly generated number identifies the session

Domain: .sharethis.com

Expires: 1 year after the cookie is set on your device

**Name: _UID**

Purpose: measures the website’s audience size

Typical content: a randomly generated number identifies the session

Domain: .scorecardresearch.com

Expires: 1 year after the cookie is set on your device

**Name: _UIDR**

Purpose: measures the website’s audience size

Typical content: a randomly generated number identifies the session

Domain: .scorecardresearch.com

Expires: 1 year after the cookie is set on your device

**Other cookies set by third party sites**

The TWI website also hosts links to various social media portals and offers options to ‘share’ information. When selecting a link and opting in to such a service, you may be presented with a cookie. TWI is not responsible for the content of third party websites and does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for further information. If you do not agree, do not use links to third parties

#####  [LinkedIn](http://www.linkedin.com/static?key=privacy_policy "LinkedIn Privacy Policy")

#####  [YouTube](http://www.youtube.com/t/privacy "YouTube Privacy Policy") (Google)

#####  [Twitter](http://www.twitter.com/privacy "Twitter Privacy Policy")

#####  [Facebook](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy "Facebook Privacy Policy")

#####  [Flickr (Yahoo)](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/flickr/details.html)

#####  [Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ "Google Privacy Policy")

**How to control and delete cookies**

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but you do not have to accept cookies and you can, should you choose at any time, reject or block the use of cookies and delete all cookies stored on your device. 

TWI does not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you. We use them to help us provide you with a better service. However, if you wish to restrict or block any cookies you can do this through your browser settings. The Help function within your browser should tell you how. 

For example, this is how it can be achieved in Microsoft Internet Explorer 8.0:

  * Press the ‘F1’ key 

  * The Help function appears. Type in ‘cookie’ in the Help search box and follow the instructions

You can also delete cookies in Microsoft Internet Explorer 8.0 by: 

  * Selecting 'Tools/Internet Options' 

  * Clicking on 'Delete' in the Browsing History section

  * Then select 'delete cookies'. 

In addition to this, options to accept, block, or require notification for the use of cookies are found under: 

  * 'Tools/Internet Options/Privacy/Advanced'. 

Please be aware however that if you choose to block cookies you may not be able to access certain features of this web site. For rejecting and deleting cookies on other web browsing platforms and mobile devices you may need to refer to your software or device manual.

[AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "About Cookies Advice") or  [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "All About Cookies Advice") are independent sites which offers a guide to the use of cookies online. You can find more general information about how to delete and control cookies through your browser at these sites. Please note that TWI is not responsible for the content of third party website sites but has provided these links in good faith to help you make an informed decision about your online privacy and cookie settings.

It may be that your concerns about cookies are related to malicious spyware. Rather than switching off cookies in your browser you may find that anti-spyware software achieves the same objective by automatically deleting cookies considered to be invasive.    

## Collection, use and security of your personal information

**What information do we collect about you and how do we use it?  
**We collect personal information that you may volunteer while using our services. 

We do not collect personal information about our visitors from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organisations. 

To access the table of personal information collected and purposes for which they are used, please click here. 

We do not collect or use personal data for any purpose other than that indicated in the table below. 

If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, we shall offer you the means to consent to this new purpose, by indicating in a check box at the point on the site where personal information is collected. Alternatively we will notify of our intentions to use your personal information for a different purpose from which it was originally collected and give you an opportunity to agree or disagree with this change. 

We do not disclose our visitors’ personal information to third parties but may pass relevant anonymous data to appropriate project partners or, in the case of examination candidates, to the appropriate certifying body. 

**How do we secure your information?  
**We do not give visitors to our websites the option of using a secure transmission method to send us their personal data other than where the Barclays / RBS WorldPay secure server is used for e-commerce transactions. 

We have implemented security polices, rules and technical measures to protect the personal information that we have under our control from:

  * unauthorised access
  * improper use or disclosure
  * unauthorised modification
  * unlawful destruction or accidental loss

All our employees and data processors, who have access to, and are associated with, the processing of personal information, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors’ personal information. 

We ensure that your personal data will not be disclosed to State institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation. 

**Access to your information and correction  
**You have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, you can contact us by:

  * sending an email to [ data.protection@twi.co.uk ](mailto:data.protection@twi.co.uk)
  * calling this telephone number +44 (0)1223 899000

We will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data which we keep about you within 40 days, although we may require you to provide proof of your identity before we disclose your personal data. We may charge up to £10 for this. 

We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove personal information that we hold on you which you think is inaccurate. 

**Privacy and cookie use compliance  
**Our privacy and cookie use policy complies with the following UK instruments and their amendments:

  * Data Protection Act 1998
  * Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003

**Changes to our privacy and cookie use policy  
**We keep our privacy and cookie use policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this webpage. This privacy and cookie use policy was last updated on 23 July 2013\. 

**How to contact us  
**If you have an enquiry or concern about our privacy and cookie use policy, please contact:

 Name / designation: |  Data Controller  
---|---  
 Address: |  Granta Park, Great Abington, Cambridge, CB21 6AL, UK  
 Phone number: |  +44 (0)1223 899000  
 Fax number: |  01223 892588  
 Email address: |   [data.protection@twi.co.uk ](mailto:data.protection@twi.co.uk)  

###  Table of personal data collected and purposes for which they are used

**  
Primary personal data / Business information  
**   
X = Volunteered by each visitor

**Primary personal data**   | 

Technical administration   
of the website

| 

Research and development

| 

Customer Administration

| 

Marketing 

| 

Trading in personal data 

| 

Contact from TWI   
  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
Name |  |  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|   |    
Gender |   |   |   |   |   |    
Address |   |  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|  |    
Email address | 

**X**

|  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|  |    
Phone / fax number |   |  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|  |    
Membership status | 

**X**

|  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|   |    
**Business Information** | 

Technical administration   
of the website

| 

Research and development

| 

Customer Administration 

| 

Marketing 

| 

Trading in personal data 

| 

Contact from TWI staff   
  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
Employer / Organisation | 

**X**

|  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|  |   
Job title |   |   |   |   |   |    
Address |  |  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|  |   
Email address |  |  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|  | 

**X**  
  
Phone / Fax number |   |  | 

**X**

|  |  | 

**X**  
  
Number of employees |   |  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|  |    
Industry sectors most closely affiliated with |   |  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|  |    
TWI technologies of interest |   |  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|  |    
TWI services and products of most interest |   |  | 

**X**

| 

**X**

|  |    
  
**Identifiers**

X = Volunteered by each visitor

**Business Information** | 

Technical administration   
of the website

| 

Research and development

| 

Customer Administration 

| 

Marketing 

| 

Trading in personal data 

| 

Contact from TWI staff   
  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
Online identifiers | 

**X**

|  | 

**X**

|  |  |   
Financial identifiers |   |   |   |   |   |    
Identifiers assigned by Public Bodies |  |  |  |  |  |   
Biometrics identifiers |  |  |  |  |  |
